THIEN NGUYEN

Phone/ Whatsapp: (+84) 775188017 | Email: ngthien2911@gmail.com | Skype: ngthien2911

SUMMARY

Service-oriented professional with more than 6 years of experience in Hospitality and Tourism Industry. Strong ability on applying technology to maximize productivity at work, familiar with using several well-developed tools and systems of multinational companies such as Traveloka, TUI Group, Hosfully. Able to work effectively both with a team and individually without supervision.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Customer Service • Interpersonal & Communication Skill • Presentation Skill • Problem-Solving • Self-management

EXPERIENCES

May 2021 - Present: Front-end developer

- Using HTML5, CSS3 for web development.
- Using ReactJs and Redux to develop sites calling APIs.
- Creating basic apps with JS and React
- Get to know Git, GitLab, and practice handling conflicts on Git
- Github: https://github.com/ngthien2911
- Project: https://ngthien2911ecommerce.netlify.app/

HOSTFULLY | Award-winning integrated Property Management Platform Technical Support Representative

July 2020 - Present

- System: Intercom, Salesforce, JIRA, Confluence.
- Key responsibilities:
 - Manage customer support email and chat queues using Intercom and Salesforce to ensure timely and accurate responses to customers while setting clear expectations.
 - Troubleshoot customer reported product issues to identify if the issue is a bug, user error or product limitation
 - Effectively communicate with engineering teams to help prioritize and resolve customer issues through a project management ticketing system
 - Improve documentation around product functionality and customer support best practices
 - Work with internal team members to influence Product, Sales, and Customer Success
 - Work closely with the Leadership Team to provide input on the growth of the business and align revenue strategy with overall company objectives

TUI GROUP | One of the world's largest leisure, travel and tourism company in the world

Operation Manager October 2018 – July 2020

- System: Asterix.
- Key responsibilities:
 - Managed destination service operation in Phu Quoc including finance activities, partnership development, tours operation, logistic management, quests satisfaction,...
 - Provided technical support and administrative support for the Phu Quoc office.
 - Served as the main contact point to work with local authorities at the airport and on the island.
 - Trained to be key account of the Vietnam Branch on using Asterix (TUI Group's standardized fully integrated system for all countries)

TRAVELOKA | Technology company aims to revolutionize human mobility with technology

Customer Support Representative April 2018 – October 2018

- System: Zendesk, Salesforce.
- Key responsibilities:
 - Managed customer cases through case management and customer database applications within allowable solving time (1 to 24 hours case by case).

- Acted as a second-tier point of escalation from the customer service team thus expected to solve cases related with ticketing, payment processing, issuance, amendment, relocation, instruction.
- Served as liaison between customer service with Payment and Ticketing Team, and thus has to formulate requests on required action and escalation needs to the right team.

VESPA ADVENTURES & ONETRIP | Travel agencies focusing on international guests

Freelancer Tour Guide February 2017 - April 2018

Led different local experience trips in Saigon for international guests such as: Saigon after dark, City tours, ...

ONETRIP & CHRISTINAS VIETNAM COMPANY LIMITED | Tech driven fully-integrated travel experience company Tour leader & Host July 2015 – February 2017

- Participated in Onetrip tour operations, including design new tours, lead tours of Onetrip Saigon & Hoian, and enhanced quests' experience on tours.
- Participated in host operations of Christina's in Saigon & Hoian including: check-in, check-out guests, manage housekeeping team, solve in-house technical issues, handle guests crises.

EDUCATION & AWARD

HO CHI MINH CITY UNIVERSITY OF INDUSTRY | HCMC, VIETNAM Bachelor of Environmental Science of engineering and management

INTERNATIONAL TOUR GUIDE LICENSE

EXTRA ACTIVITIES

IVC - INTERNATIONAL VOLUNTEER CLUB Volunteer